Help is only 140 million miles away
The Martian is a drama, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Ridley Scott.
During a manned mission to Mars, Astronaut Mark Watney is presumed
dead after a fierce storm and left behind by his crew.
But Watney has survived and finds himself stranded
and alone on the hostile planet.
With only meager supplies, he must draw upon his ingenuity, wit and spirit to
subsist and find a way to signal to Earth that he is alive.
Mark Watney, played by Matt Damon.
Melissa Lewis, played by Jessica Chastain.
Annie Montrose, played by Kristen Wiig.
Theodore "Teddy" Sanders, played by Jeff Daniels.
Rick Martinez, played by Michael Peña.
Mitch Henderson, played by Sean Bean.
The Martian is a 2015 epic science fiction film directed by
Ridley Scott from a screenplay by Drew Goddard.
Based on Andy Weir's 2011 novel, and distributed by 20th Century Fox, the film stars Matt Damon, alongside an ensemble cast featuring Jessica
Chastain, Jeff Daniels, Kristen Wiig, Chiwetel Ejiofor, Sean Bean, Michael Peña, Kate Mara, Sebastian Stan, and Mackenzie Davis.
The film depicts an astronaut's struggle to survive on Mars after being
left behind and NASA's efforts to return him to Earth.
Producer Simon Kinberg began developing the film after
Fox optioned the novel in March 2013.
Goddard, who adapted the novel into a screenplay, was initially attached to direct, but production was only
approved after Scott replaced Goddard as director and Damon was cast as the main character.
Filming began in November 2014 and lasted about 70
days, on a $108 million budget.
Twenty sets were built on one of the largest sound
stages in the world in Budapest, Hungary.
Wadi Rum in Jordan was also used for exterior filming.
The Martian premiered at the 2015 Toronto International Film Festival on September 11, 2015, and was released in the
United Kingdom on September 30, and in the United States on October 2, in 2D, 3D, IMAX 3D and 4DX formats.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed over $630 million worldwide, becoming the
tenth-highest-grossing film of 2015, as well as Scott's highest-grossing film to date.
Named by the National Board of Review and by the American Film Institute one of the top-ten films of 2015, The
Martian received numerous accolades, including seven nominations at the 88th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of spacecraft, planet mars,
based on novel or book, nasa, isolation.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.